Pratik Pandab

Data Scientist

Data Science Professional with a B.Tech in Computer Science & Engineering, with 1+ years of work experience. Aiming to leverage research experience and proven working knowledge of advanced emerging data-based technologies. Exceptional knowledge of developing DL/ML Products and analyzing Real-world Data.

Contact

Address

Shahdol, MP, 484117

E-mail

pratikpandav28@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/pratikpandab

WWW

https://pratik-1999.github.io/

Skills

Machine Learning	Excellent
Deep Learning	Excellent
BigQuery	Excellent
Tensorflow	Excellent
PyTorch	Excellent
Statistical Analysis	Excellent
Python	Excellent
Data Studio	Excellent
Tableau	Excellent

Work History

2022-02 -Current

Data Scientist

Cutshort, Pune, Maharashtra

- Worked in a cross-functional role with stakeholders from Technical, Marketing and Customer Success Teams to identify impact of various initiatives, value-based features and test coordinations.
- Utilized advanced querying, visualization and analytics tools to analyze and process complex real-world data sets.
- Developed models based on statistical analysis to help recruiters identify major pain-points in their hiring process.
- Identified, measured and recommended improvement strategies for KPIs across business areas.

2021-07 -2022-02

Systems Engineer

TCS, Bangalore, Karnataka

- Worked on Data Engineering and Analysis of Integrated Patient Safety Decision Fabric.
- Implemented and optimized ETL pipelines to automate previously tedious data extraction process with minimal human supervision.
- Reduced report on-boarding time by 70% as compared to previous workflow.
- Review and analyze processed data batches and performance indicators to locate bugs and correct them.

2021-02 -2021-06

R&D Project Intern

TCS, Mumbai, Maharashtra

- Conducted design and development to build and optimize Deep Learning Software.
- Minimized human intervention in workflow phases by 90%.
- Created Graphical User Interface for easier navigation through functionalities.
- Planned, developed and executed experimental test

programs for new acceptability criteria.

 Maintained weekly project status and updates on resulting outcomes that could act as guiding framework for further development.

2020-05 -2020-08

Data Scientist

DeepLogic AI, New Delhi, Delhi

- Developed working prototypes of Computer-Vision based models, evaluating and comparing metrics on real-world data sets.
- Built a Deep Learning model to monitor standard operating procedures at workspaces.
- Developed an adaptive threshold technique to reduced false-positives by 80% in the models.

Education

2017-07 -2021-06

B.Tech: Computer Science And Engineering

S.A.T.I. - Vidisha

- CGPA: 8.1
- Published a Patent on "Soil Monitoring Device for Efficient Biome Management and Crop Guidance".
- Finalist of NEC 2019, IIT Bombay

Certifications

2020-08	Udacity - Machine Learning Engineer Nanodegree
2019-08	Deeplearning.ai - Tensorflow Developer Certification